<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jacob J Webber</title>
    <link>https://jacobjwebber.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jacob J Webber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 20:07:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jacobjwebber.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Are We All Living in a Simulation?</title>
      <link>https://jacobjwebber.github.io/post/simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 20:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobjwebber.github.io/post/simulation/</guid>
      <description>Where do we come from? Why are we here? Do we even exist? The quest to answer these questions is so embedded in our nature that to ask them almost defines us as humans. But we are not the primitive creatures we once were. As our understanding of the world reaches new levels of sophistication, surely so must our solutions to these age old problems.
That is the belief of an increasing number of scientists and tech luminaries such as Elon Musk, who recently stated that the odds were a billion to one against us living in a &amp;ldquo;base reality&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Personal Website with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://jacobjwebber.github.io/post/new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 20:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobjwebber.github.io/post/new-blog/</guid>
      <description>New Blog! Where better to start a new blog than a blog post about how I made this blog.
Over the last Christmas holidays I have started playing around with the Go programming languages. Wow! What a great programming language! At work I mainly wrote Java code, and at University I mainly use C. Go seems to combine a lot of the positive aspects of both. It also has a very interesting and neat model for writing parallel or concurrent programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webber’s World: In Praise of Love and Mediocrity</title>
      <link>https://jacobjwebber.github.io/post/webbers-world-love-mediocre/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 20:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobjwebber.github.io/post/webbers-world-love-mediocre/</guid>
      <description>There was no way I wasn’t going to enjoy Birdman when I went to see it at the cinema last night. My date Patty, well, just sitting next to Patty could make watching any old drek worthwhile. Nevertheless I enjoyed Birdman more than can be explained away by good viewing company. It charts the story of a former A-list film star’s desire to make the transition from low art to high art as he directs and stars in a Broadway production of his own adaptation of a Raymond Carver story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webber’s World: Hummus</title>
      <link>https://jacobjwebber.github.io/post/webbers-world-hummus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 20:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobjwebber.github.io/post/webbers-world-hummus/</guid>
      <description>My flatmate Gemmagen doesn’t have the greatest dining etiquette. I say that not to be unduly insulting, merely to prepare you for the next sentence I will write, one that might, without this warning, cause shock and revulsion from the more sophisticated readers of this column. In the course of eating some hummus on rye, Gemmagen had put her table knife into her mouth.
Apologies for the shocking nature of that statement but it is pertinent for the accurate telling of this story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webber’s World: Dinner at KFC Edinburgh Southside</title>
      <link>https://jacobjwebber.github.io/post/webbers-world-kfc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 20:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacobjwebber.github.io/post/webbers-world-kfc/</guid>
      <description>Supper with my dear friend Jamie Scott can often be a bit of a chore. Although his company is a delight, sharing food with him is a challenge because he is a selfish and greedy little prick. This was not a concern when between us was KFC’s masterful Deluxe Boneless Feast. I knew that however much dear Jamie clawed and grabbed at the box, which was supposed to be in our common ownership, there was no way we wouldn’t both be leaving the restaurant very full up indeed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>